Guide to the Malcolm Goldstein Papers MSS.350
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: Writing
  - Subseries A: Unpublished Drafts and Interviews
    - "Some Glimpses of Jim Tenney" original manuscript, December 25, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - "Some Glimpses of Jim Tenney" for Soundings Magazine #13, December 25, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - "Sound Textures" (Dictionary of Contemporary Music), 1971 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - "Sounding an Open Space" at Concordia College Montreal, May 24, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - "'Sounding' as the realization (external gesture) of internal vision" - Grant Proposal, October 25, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - "Sounding the Full Circle" - letter to Gregory, April 9, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - "Soundings for Solo Violin" for Music Works, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Statements for program notes [alphabetical] [1 of 2], [undated] (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Statements for program notes [alphabetical] [2 of 2], [undated] (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Submission for Elaine Summers Book Project, 2017 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - "Texture" for Dictionary of 20th Century Music, January, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - "To carry through in form" reflections on a performance of John Cage's 'Theater Piece' for Sounding the Full CIrcle, August 20, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Transcription of Interviews with Malcolm Goldstein, 2013 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Transcript of Interview with Malcolm Goldstein, 2020 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - "Typography of a Sound Mind" [Never published bound draft], [undated] (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - "Typography of a Sound Mind" [with correspondence], [undated] (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - "Typography of a Sound Mind" [annotated draft] [1 of 2], July 15, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - "Typography of a Sound Mind" [annotated draft] [2 of 2], July 15, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - "Typography of a Sound Mind" [correspondence], April 6, 2011 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - "Typography of a Sound Mind" - on structural improvisation composition, [undated] (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - "When a canon is more than a canon as in Charles Ives' 'Arguments'" [unpublished essay], 2003-2004 (Box 15, Folder 3, Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Subseries B: Published
    Subseries B is comprised of published versions of articles.
    Materials are arranged alphabetically by title of publication followed by the title of Malcolm's article or piece within the publication. Articles written in languages other than English are indicated in square brackets.
    - "Ad libitum: musica de verdere" No. 10 - "Jade Mountain Soundings", 2003 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "American Music" vol. 26, no.4 - "Some anecdotal evidence", Winter, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - "Aspekte Der Freien Improvisation in Der Musik" - "Improvisation as a process of discovery" [German], 2011 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Ballade" no.4 - "Politics of Improvisation" [Swedish], 1989/1990 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "Berliner Musik Studien 14: Sabine Feisst" - "Soundings" [German], 1997 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - "BMI Music World" - issue with article by Cole Gagne, Summer, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - "Circuit" vol. 28, no.2 - Interview and "Theatre Piece" [French and English], 1997 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - "Contact Quarterly" vol.10, no.1 - "Notes on the Gesture of Sound", Winter, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - "Der Tanz der Dinge" - "Portrait: Malcolm Goldstein vom sein + tun + lassen" [German], March-May, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - "Dissonance" - "Leroy Jenkins and Malcolm Goldstein: Portraits zweier improvisierender und komponiererder Geiger", February, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - "The Downtown Review" vol.3, no.1 & 2 - "The Evolution of Marin's Song, Illuminated", Fall-Spring, 1981/1982 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - "Dramatika" no.1 - "Illuminations from Fantastic Gardens", [undated] (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "Dramatika" no.14" no.29 - "Soundings", Spring, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "Du- Die Zeitschrift der Kultur" no.5 John Cage Issue - "Marin's Song, Illuminated", May, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - "Evenings of New Music no.6/ Bratislava '95: Morceaux enforme de poire" - "A brutal bit of these times", 1995 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - "Forum Neue Musik - Konzerte im Sensdesaal" - "The Seasons: Vermont/Winter" and "Theater Piece (John Cage", November 17, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "Frog Peak Anthology" - "Still Life", 1992 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - "The Frog Peak Music Book" - "wood stone metal skin, with voice" and "the violence of small sounds", 1995 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - "From Wheelock Mountain" - Music and Writings by Malcolm Goldstein", 1975 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - "Hans Otte: Klangrum: Rumsklang" - "Alltagsmusik" [German and English], September 1, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - "Heidelberger Festival fur experimentelle Literatur und Musik" [German and English], December, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - "High Performance" vol.4, no.2- with Alison Knowles, Summer, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - "Institute for Studies in American Music Newsletter" vol. 12, no.2 - "Improvisation: Towards a Whole Musician in a Fragmented Society", May, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - "Interrelation" - "Potluck" installation of Mineko Grimmer [English and Japanese], September-October, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "Inventionen" Festival Neuer Musik Berlin [German], 1989 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "Karlsplatz: Wiener Festwochen" - "Karlsplatz Resonanz" and Interview [German], 1983 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - "Kursiv-Brandherde (1): Jahrbuch 2008" - "quamaneq; shaking with joy" [English, German] (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "Le Canard" no.17 - "The Politics of Improvisation" [French], Winter, 2004/2005 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "Le Tavole Della Legge" - "The Life Cycle of Stones" [Italian], 1994 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "Lehigh University Art Galleries: Ideas from Individual Impressions and Marks: Prints of Non-Printmakers" - "Marin's Song, Illuminated", November 1988-January 1989 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - "Leonardo" vol.20, no.4 - "The Future of Music", 1987 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - "Los Angeles Festival: John Cage Celebration" - "Eight Whiskus", September 3-27, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "Manipulation: A Judson Publication" - "State of the Nation", 1967 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - "Moltkerei Werkstatt: Projekte 1981-1994" - "Violin Solos the (Whole) World Plays or The 'Third' World Within Us" [German] (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "Museet for Samtidskunst: Acustica International Festival Lydrejse" - "Typography of a Sound Mind" and "Zwischen (zwei) Raumen" [German, English], 1996 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Musicworks" no. 46 - "The Gesture of Sounding", "The Gesture of Improvisation", "Soweto Stomp", Spring, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "Musicworks" no. 64 - "Searching Out the Sounding Line", Spring, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "Musicworks" no. 77 - "The Politics of Improvisation", "Improvisation: People Making Music", Summer, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - "Musicworks" no. 78 - "Improvisation: Towards a Whole Musician in a Fragmented Society", "The Gesture of Improvisation", "Being in the Sound", Fall, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Musicworks" no. 93 - "Malcolm Goldstein: portrait of an artistic practice at its heights", Fall, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - "Musicworks" Postcard Collection - "Jade Mountain Soundings", 2004 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - "Musik fur eine Stadt" - "Reflections on the workshop in Winsen" [English and German], 2003 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "Musiktagung" - "Soundings", "The Politics of Imrpovisation", "Sounding the Fragility of the Line" [German], March, 1992; May, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - "MusikTexte" no. 28/29 - "The Politics of Improvisation", "Sounding the Fragility of Line", "Dialogue Between Gesture and Sound" [German], March, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - "MusikTexte" no. 46/47 Fur John Cage - "Gentle Rain Preceeding Mushrooms" [German], December, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - "MusikTexte" no. 99 - Philip Corner/ Peter N. Wilson [German], December, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - "MusikTexte" no. 101 - "Two Silences" [German], May, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "MusikTexte" no. 112 - "Becoming Song" for Jim Tenney [German], February, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "NachtCageTag" - "Eight Whiskus", "Windowwhiskusounding", February, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "Neue Zeitschrift fur Musik" no. 3 - "You can do anything, starting from nothing", Interview, May-June, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "New Music America" Houston Festival Foundation - "Improvisation: People Making Music", 1986 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "New Music America" Walker Art Center Festival, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - "Nie Wieder Kunst" - "Ishi/man waxati" [German, English], August, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Compact Disc enclosed in book.
    - "Non Capovolgere" no.15 - "Cento anni di suoni" [Italian], October, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - "Oltre Il SIlenzio" no.2 - "Searching the Sounding Line" [Italian], October, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "On the wall/ On the air: Artists make noise" - "Marin's Song Illuminated, December-January, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "Percussive Notes" vol. 21 no. 3 - "The Gesture of Improvisation", March, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - "Pieces 3" edited by Michael Byron - "With thoughts for Erik Satie", "A summary of focus", "To carry through in the form", 1977 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - "Pro Musica Nova"- HR Ensemble for New Music, May, 1986; May 1990 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - "Real Art Ways" - "The Seasons: Vermont", February 26, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - "Revue & Corrigee" no. 35 - "Conversation" with Jerome Joy, March, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - "Roland- The Magazine of the ICA's Visual Art Programme" Issue 1 - "Illuminations from Fantastic Gardens", May, 2009 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - "A Sanctuary for the Arts: Judson Memorial Church and the Avant-Garde 1954-1977", October, 2010 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - "Scores: An Anthology of New Music" Selection and Commentary by Roger Johnson - "Yosha's Morning Song", 1981 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - "Signal to Noise" no. 44 - "Bowed but not broken", Interview, Winter, 2007 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "Sonorita Prospettiche" - "The Seasons: Vermont" [English, Italian], 1982 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "Sound Visions" - "Two Silences" [English, German], 2005 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - "Sounding the Full Circle: concerning music improvisation adn other related matters" by Malcolm Goldstein, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "Soundings: Ives, Ruggles, Varese" edited by Peter Garland, cover by Alison Knowles - "Sirens for Edgard Varese", "Majority-1964", Spring, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - "Soundings" no. 11 - "On the first day of spring there were forty pianos", 1981 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - "Soundings Thirteen: The music of James Tenney" - "Some glimpses of Jim Tenney", 1984 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - "String Anthology Supplement" - "upon the string, within the bow...breathing", [undated] (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - "Charles E. Ives -- String Quartet No. 2 -- Ives Society Critical Edition" with Edited Drafts, Correspondence, Research, Scores, 1954, 1965, 1970, 2003-2017, undated (Box 51, Folder 11-14, Box 52, Folder 1-10)
    - "Symphony No. 2" Charles E. Ives: For Large Orchestra [full score, see also "Ives Project"], 1951 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - "Temporale: Edizioni Studio Dabbeni" - "Improvisation: Towards a Whole Musician in a Fragmented Society", "Jade Mountain Soundings", "Sounding the Fragility of Line" [Italian, English], March-April, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - "Tone Roads West: Poetry and New Music" Sante Fe Council for the Arts, March 17-20, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - "Twentieth Century Music for Young Students" Margaret K. Farish - "Upon the string, within the bow...breathing", 1992 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - "Twenty One Pages for John Cage: on the occasion of his 75th Birthday" compiled and edited by Larry Stein, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - "Violin Improvisation Studies" vol. 2 no. 9 - "Sounding the Fragility of Line", "gentle rain preceeding mushrooms", November, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - "Visuele Partituren" - "Jade Mountain Soundings" [Dutch], 1986 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - "A Voice in the Village: Howard Moody 20 Years on Washington Square" Judson Memorial Church - "Illuminations from Fantastic Gardens", March, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Warebrook Festival [Modified Berlin Talk], 2004 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - "WDR: Acustica International 1985 Horspiele" - "The Edges of Sound Within" [German], September-October, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - "WDR: Acustica International 1985 Horspiele" - "The Edges of Sound Within" Program Booklet of West German Radio Festival [German], September-October, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - "WDR: Horspiele 2 Im Westdeutschen Rundfunk" Acoustica Art/Radio - "The edges of sound within" [German], 1985 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - "WDR: Horspiele 2 Im Westdeutschen Rundfunk" - "Typography of a Sound Mind", "Windowhiskusounding" [German], October, 1991; 1992 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - "WDR: Horspiele 2 Im Westdeutschen Rundfunk" - "Zwischen (zwei) Raumen", "Ishi/time changing spaces" [German], December, 1993; 1998 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - "WDR: Studio Akustiche Kunst -Sound Art Festival Acustica International New York-Montreal" - "Ishi/time changing spaces" [English, German], April-May, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - "WDR: Studio Akustiche Kunst Programm" Collected program booklets of "Horspiel" creations at West German Radio (WDR) Cologne [German], July, 1995- February, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - "WDR: Studio Akustiche Kunst - Sound Klangreise Journey" West German Radio, Cologne - "Typography of a Sound Mind", "Zwischen (zwei) Raumen", "Versuch einer grundlichen Violinschule" [German], 1997 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - "Wittener Tage: Kammermusik" - "through deserts of time" [German], April, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - "Yellow Springs Review: The Letter of the Yellow Springs Institute for Contemporary Studies and the Arts", Winter, 1983-1984 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: Correspondence
    Subseries C contains correspondence received by Malcolm Goldstein. There are a small number of instances where correspondence was written by Malcolm Goldstein.
    Materials are arranged by surname of the sender. If material was written by Malcolm Goldstein this is indicated in square brackets and is still organized in relation to correspondent. Occasionally correspondence relating to a specific music project remains in the folder relating to that project.
    - Agosin, Marjorie - [Wellesley College], July 16, 1993; [undated] (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Albertson, Dan, 2005-2013 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Ashley, Robert - [Tone Roads], April 18, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Baron, Carol K., July 3, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Bartlett, Steve, January 4, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Berge, Carol, May 10, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Black, Robert, April 6, 1984; July 15, 1984; January 28, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Bonomo, Gabriele - ["Temporale"], 1998-2000 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Brakhage, Stan, [1982-1987] (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Bryars, Gavin, July 26, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Byron, Michael, May 4, 1977; January 28, 2000; July 1, 2005; July 25, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Cage, John, [1965-1966]; [undated] (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Cage, John - Regarding "Eight Whiskus", "Chorals", "Royanji", "Theater Piece", [1967-1996] (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Cameron, Dan and Wendy Perron [Judson Project Show], September 11, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Canada Council for the Arts, 2018 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Carter, Elliot, September 24, 1961; [undated] (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Carpenter, Edmund, December 21, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Carroll, James, March 1, 1982; February 10, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Celli, Joseph, [undated] (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Childs, Barney, January 21, 1977; May 27, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Chodos, Rafael - ["Some Anecdotal Evidence"], December 23, 2010 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Cole, Peter and Adina Hoffman - Regarding score to poetry of Taha Muhammad Ali [Ibis Press], February 9, 1998; December 21, 2001; January 8, 2003; October 27, 2009 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Conz, Francesco - Regarding Henry Martin, June 1, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Copland, Aaron, June 4, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Corner, Philip, [1998-2013]; [undated] (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Corner, Philip, December, 1959; [2000]; [undated] (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Corner, Philip, [undated] (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Corner, Philip, [undated] (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Corner, Philip, October 26, 1980; December 18,2006; [undated] (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Corner, Philip, [undated] (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Corner, Philip, [1992-2002][undated] (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Corner, Philip, 2000; [undated] (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Corner, Philip, 2000; [undated] (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Cowell, Henry - [Tone Roads], June 4, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Emmerik, Paul, 1999; 2003 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Estrin, Marc [from Malcolm Goldstein], February 20, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Fisher, Mark ["The Wire"], November 24, 2008 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Flynn, George ["Four Pieces"], August 3, 1971; October 4, 1971; December 24, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Forti, Simone, Summer, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Fortier, Paul-andre - ["Vertiges"] [French], March 3, 2012 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Foss, Lukas - ["Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"], [1985] (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Fox, Jim, May 27, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Frog Peak Music, May 23, 1997; June 25, 1997; December 2, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Galeano, Eduardo, May 23, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Garland, Peter, [1984-2013] (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Garland, Peter, [1975-1993] (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Garland, Peter, [1997-2003] (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Garland, Peter, [1999-2012] (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Gervais, Raymond, 2001;2011 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Hammann, Barbara, February 22, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Hendricks, Jon - [Judson Memorial Church], September 22, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Hicks, Michael [from Malcolm Goldstein], April 3, 2008; January 11, 2009 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Higgins, Dick, May 18, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Hitchcock, Wiley [Ives scholar with annotated version of "When a canon is more than a canon, as in Charles Ives' 'Arguments'"], February 10, 2004 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Hostetler, Zona, August 18, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Johns, Jasper, May 25, 2006 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Johnson, Tom, April 9, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Johnston, Jill, June 9, 2005; 2011 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Kahn, Doug - ["Fire Over Water"], April 23, 1986; May 5, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Kakinuma, Toshie, [1999-2007] (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Kasemets, Udo, [1998-2005] (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Kaul, Matthias, [2002-2013][undated] (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Kirkpatrick, John [Ives Project], [1965-1986] (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Knowles, Alison ["Breath River Route"], [1967-2005][undated] (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Kostelanetz, Richard, December 20, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Kubaczek, Martin, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Le Guin, Ursula, June 10-12, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Lewis, George [from Malcolm Goldstein], December 5, 2008 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Lloyd, Lew [Foundation for Contemporary Performing Arts], August 12, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Lukoszevieze, Arthur, [2000-2002][undated] (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Lukoszevieze, Arthur, [2000-2002][undated] (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Mac Low, Jackson, [1989-2002] (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Marder, Norma, March 9, 1978; [undated] (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Marion, Louis-Michel, 2010; 2013 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Martin, Henry, August 22, 2010; October 2, 2011 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Maus, Andreas and Karen Frank ["Die Reise des Spatzen"], 1993-1994; 2000 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Mayers, Natasha ["Resonances de Babel"], 2001; [undated] (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Meyer, Felix [Sacher Foundation, Basel, "Sirens for Edgard Varese"], [2005-2013] (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Miller, Leta [Professor of Music], April 8, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Miodini, Cate ["Marin's Song, Illuminated"], February 6, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Miranda, Anthony [Violin Teacher], October 14, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Moss, David, July 20, 1980; April 17, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Nancarrow, Conlon [Tone Roads], December 6, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Nelson, Mark, 2002; 2013 (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Neuhaus, Max, [undated] (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Nordin, Ingo Loco, [2001-2006] (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Oja, Carol J. [The College of William and Mary], April 26, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Oliveros, Pauline, [1979-1999] (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Ortenberg, Edgar [Violin Teacher], March 13, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Otte, Hans ["Alltagsmusik"], [1990-2006] (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Paik, Nam June, [undated] (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Perlis, Vivian [Yale University], October 23, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Phillips, Barre, May 31, 2006; January, 2011 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Piekut, Benjamin - Regarding Charlotte Moorman, February, 2008 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Rabe, Folke, December 21, 2006; October 9, 2009 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Reck, David, 1968; [undated] (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Rothlem, Arlene, [August, 1959] (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Rudd, Roswell, [1980] (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Rudhyar, Dan [Tone Roads], March, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Rust, Dorothea ["Uber land unter"], [1995-2012][undated] (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Scelsi, Giacinto, [undated] (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Schapiro, Meyer, November 19, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Schneeman, Carolee, [1988-1995][undated] (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Schneeman, Carolee ["Cycladic Imprints", "Correspondence Course"], [undated] (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Schoning, Klaus [WDR: Studio Akustische Kunst], [1984-2004] (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Schwarzer, Stefan [Musik und Text], March 27, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Snow, Michael, August 21, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Stiebler, Ernst Albrecht, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Suter, Marie ["Winter"], [undated] (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Tenney, James [1 of 2], [1974-1993][undated] (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Tenney, James and Eric Smigel [2 of 2], [2007] (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Thomas, Rudolf [Columbia Composer's Concert], [late 1950's] (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Ting, Li-Ping ["Fragments of the Wall"], [2002-2004] (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Varese, Louise, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Villars, Chris [Feldman Homages], March 26, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Vunderink, Todd, 2020 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Waxman, Donald [Galaxy Music Corporation], August 18, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Wiedemann, Carsten [Dancer for "Theater Piece"], December 3, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Williams, Christopher ["Jade Mountain Soundings"], November 22, 2011 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Wilson, Peter Niklaus, [1997-2003][undated] (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Wolff, Christian ["Bread and Roses"], [1972-1998] (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Wolpe, Stefan [Music copyist work], [late 1960's] (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Yates, Peter, December 7, 1965; November 15, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Young, Ben [Radio program], September 9, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Zinn, Howard, [1996-2005] (Box 25, Folder 36)
- Series III: Publicity
  Series III comprises three subseries: Reviews, Photographs, and Ephemera. Each subseries is described more fully below.
  - Subseries A: Reviews
    Subseries A is comprised of reviews written about Malcolm Goldstein's CD Recordings, Ensemble Pieces, and other performances.
    Folder titles are derived from Malcolm Goldstein's notations and are reflections of his method for categorizing reviews. Each general category of review has been listed alphabetically.